Guide to the Edward Sewall Guthrie papers, [ca. 1907-1962]
Guthrie, Edward Sewall papers, [ca. 1907-1962]
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Edward Sewall Guthrie papers, [ca. 1907-1962]
21-20-800
Edward Sewall Guthrie, 1880-1964.
5.4 cubic ft.
Correspondence, charts, photographs, printed material.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library.
Correspondence with the American Dairy Association, other agricultural organizations, manufacturers of dairy machinery, commercial laboratories, and other professors of dairy science concerning experiments, studies of cultured cream, butter making, stock judging at Cornell, and the naming of the dairy building after William A. Stocking.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Professor of Dairy Industry, Cornell University.
Edward S. Guthrie received his M.S. and Ph.D. from Cornell in 1910 and 1913.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Correspondence with the American Dairy Association, other agricultural organizations, manufacturers of dairy machinery, commercial laboratories, and other professors of dairy science concerning experiments, studies of cultured cream, butter making, stock judging at Cornell, and the naming of the dairy building after William A. Stocking; also, Professor Guthrie's laboratory notebooks, texts of various broadcasts he gave (1929-1934) for the Cornell Agricultural Hour on stations WEAI and WESG, his articles, some charts and photographs relating to dairy processes, annual department letters (Nos. 1-7, 1949-1954, 1957) sent to alumni, and printed material.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Guthrie, Edward Sewall, 1880-1964.; American Dairy Association.; Cornell University--Faculty.; New York State College of Agriculture and Life Sciences--Faculty.; WEAI (Radio station: Ithaca, N.Y.); WESG (Radio station: Ithaca, N.Y.)
Subjects:
Dairy science.; Milk--Research.; Butter--Production.; Cream.; Dairy stock.
Form and Genre Terms:
Photographs.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- American Dairy Science Association. Necrology Com., 1946-1947, and 1953-1954 (Box 1)
- 880 - A Study of the Body of Cultured Cream, 1952 (Box 1)
- I - Alumni Letter, 1949 (Box 1)
- Cornell Dairy Science Association, 1940 (Box 1)
- Army (Box 1)
- Cornell Dairy Sceicne Association, 1941-1942 (Box 1)
- Metals D. Sc., 1949-1950 (Box 1)
- Six Year Old Butter (Box 1)
- Committee of N.Y. Butter Manufacturers (Box 1)
- Membership and Subscription B...(rest ripped off) (Box 1)
- Butter Conference, Dec. 7-8, 1944 (Box 1)
- Creamery List, N.Y. (Box 1)
- Cleaners (Box 1)
- Cream Neutralizers (Box 1)
- Report to President of the Cornell Dairy Science Association by the Industrial Relations Committee (Box 1)
- Cornell (Box 1)
- Cherry Burrell - Corp. - Metal Chrms. (Box 1)
- Misc. Personal (Box 1)
- Creighton's Creamery (Box 1)
- Concentrated Milk (Box 1)
- Cornell Dairy Science Assoc. (Box 1)
- Germantown Mfg. Co. (Box 1)
- Dairy Industries Society International (Box 1)
- Equipment (Box 1)
- C.W. Fairbank (Box 1)
- Oxidixed Flavors (Box 1)
- Franeau Cooling and Deodorizing (Box 1)
- The Guilder Corporation (Box 1)
- History of Marketing Butter (Box 1)
- Medal - H.P. Hood and Sons, Walter S. Green (Box 1)
- H.P. Hood and Sons, 1953 (Box 1)
- Inside Cornell (Box 1)
- K and J (Box 1)
- Ludington, V.D. (Box 1)
- Judging Teams, 1916, 1919 (Box 1)
- Student Judging, 1922 (Box 1)
- Student Judging - Old Records, 1923, National (Box 1)
- Misc., 1946-1947 (Box 1)
- Misc., 1948 (Box 1)
- Student Judging, 1932 (Box 1)
- Student Judging, 1933 (Box 1)
- Student Judging, 1934 (Box 1)
- Student Judging, 1935 (Box 1)
- Student Judging, 1936, National (Box 1)
- Eastern States, 1938 (Box 1)
- 1938, Judging, National (Box 1)
- Judging Team, 1937 (Box 1)
- Judging Team, 1939 (Box 1)
- Judging Team, 1940 (Box 1)
- Judging Team - Eastern S. Colls., 1941 (Box 1)
- Three loose mounted photographs, and some loose papers (Box 1)
- Eastern States - 1947 (Box 1)
- More loose material (Box 1)
- Misc., 1950 (Box 1)
- Misc., 1951 (Box 1)
- Misc., 1952 (Box 2)
- 1953, Misc. - G (Box 2)
- Misc., 1954 (Box 2)
- 1955 (Box 2)
- Misc., 1949 (Box 2)
- Oxidation Flavor (Box 2)
- Horace S. Smith, Jr. (Box 2)
- Horace S. Smith, Jr. (Box 2)
- Dolan Machinery Co., Inc. (Box 2)
- Vogt Method of Making Flake Buttermilk (Box 2)
- ADSA, 1959 (Box 2)
- American Cottage Cheese Institute (Box 2)
- Classes and Staff (Box 2)
- First Butter Plant (Box 2)
- Cultured Cream Correspondence (Box 2)
- BLH and ESG Fatty Acids (Box 2)
- Brochures - Correspondence (Box 2)
- A-B Seminar (Box 2)
- Brochures and Replies - Dairy Depts. and Libraries (Box 2)
- Mrs. Mildred Parker Seese (?) (Box 2)
- First Creamery, 1956 (Box 2)
- First Creamery (Box 2)
- Misc., 1955-1956 (Box 2)
- Misc., 1956 (Box 2)
- Dairy 2, May 2, 1942, Frederick Maxwell (Box 2)
- Misc., 1957 (Box 2)
- Hood, 1956-1958 (Box 2)
- Misc., 1958 (Box 3)
- 1959 (Box 3)
- 1960 (Box 3)
- 1961 (Box 3)
- 1962 (Box 3)
- 1963 (Box 3)
- 1964 (Box 3)
- Correspondence - Cultured Cream, 1960-1961 (Box 3)
- Stabilizers (Box 3)
- 1952, Cultivated Cream Bus. - Cultured Cream, 1960 (Box 3)
- (Bunch of empty folders) (Box 3)
- Envelope containing photograph (Box 3)
- Jensen Machinery Company, Inc. material (loose) including brochures and photograph (Box 3)
- Challenge Cream and Butter Assoc. (Box 3)
- Unlabeled (Cornell Dairy Science Assoc. Materials?) (Box 3)
- Misc. - Special Communications (Box 3)
- Misc. (Box 3)
- Dean Mann (Box 3)
- Encyclopedia Britannica (Box 3)
- Correspondence to keep (Box 3)
- Agricultural Missions Foundation (Box 3)
- Notebook containing annual letters to Alumni Dept. of Dairy Industry, 1949-1957 (Box 3)
- Bundle of envelopes (contain radio broadcasts, re butter, buttermilk, etc.), WEAI, WESG, 1929-1934, Agr. Coll. (Box 3)
- Unlabeled envelope (contains printed papers of U.S. Dept. of Agriculture, Bureau of Dairy Industry; what appear to be mss. of various reports, by Gurthie; some correspondence) (Box 4)
- Loose: some papers dealing with milk (published?) by E.S. Gurthie and B.L. Herrington (Box 4)
- Envelope of correspondence: American Dairy Science Association, U. of Wisconsin, Michigan State (Box 4)
- Loose: "Crowley's Quarterly," (2 issues), and some milk sheets (Box 4)
- Envelope: marked "culture cream" - contains correspondence (Box 4)
- Loose: Misc. reports, accounts, calculations; several newspapers and clippings; cow accounts or production records(?) (Box 4)
- Envelope marked "Hood 1957 " (Box 4)
- Folder: Heathization (Box 4)
- "Crowley's Quarterly" (Box 4)
- Folder: Time of Lactation, Winter and Summer Feeding, BLH, ESG, 1956 (Box 4)
- Letters about bulletin (folder) (Box 4)
- Unlabeled folder: Typescripts of report (Box 4)
- Pamphlet: Appellants Brief, United States Court of Customs and Patent Appeals (Box 4)
- Envelope of correspondence with Arthur D. Little, Inc., Research-Engineering-Investigation (Box 4)
- Envelope containing mounted photograph. List of signatures clipped to outside (Box 4)
- Loose: Milk Flavor Clinic materials (many dupls.); clipping; New York State Association of Milk Sanitarians Newsletter (Box 4)
- "Old Ornage Houses, Organe County, New York," Vol. II, by Mildred Parker Seese (Box 4)
- Book: Old Organe Houses by Mildred Parker Seese (Box 4)
- Bundle of Correspondence (Box 4)
- Loose: various notes, papers, correspondence (Box 4)
- Briefcase containign tabulations (Box 5)
- Four Notebooks labeled E.S. Gurthrie, Cultured Cream (Box 5)
- Papery Flavor Studies - (hard cover notebook) (Box 5)
- E.S. Guthrie, Stocking Hall - (hard cover notebook) (Box 5)
- E.S. Guthrie, Stocking, 1953-1954 - (hard cover notebook) (Box 5)
- Frank Beck, Oct. 22, 1936 - (hard cover notebook) (Box 5)
- E.S. Guthrie, Book 2, Cod Liver Oil, etc. - (hard cover notebook) (Box 5)
- Butter Research, J. Campbell - (hard cover notebook) (Box 5)
- Oxidized Flavors, Mar. 1951, E.S. Guthrie - (hard cover notebook) (Box 5)
- D.B. Hand, Aug. 8, 1940 - (hard cover notebook) (Box 5)
- E.S. Guthrie, Stocking Hall, 1955 - (hard cover notebook) (Box 5)
- Book Started Feb. 25, 195?, Warren family P17, Cornell P21, Ascorbic Acid, Light, Flavor. Guthrie, Hand, Shep. - (hard cover notebook) (Box 5)
- E.S. Guthrie, Nov. 1939 - (hard cover notebook) (Box 5)
- E.S. Guthrie, Stocking, ESG and BLH, 1954 - (hard cover notebook) (Box 5)
- Loose sheet of tabulations (Box 5)
- Oxidized Flavors, 1935, E.S. Guthrie, Tyler and Sheperd (Box 5)
- E.S. Guthrie, Buttermilk (no writing inside) (Box 5)
- Guthrie and Scheib, 1935, Butter from Isolated Bacteria, E.S. Guthrie (Box 5)
- E.S. Guthrie, Oxidized Flavor Studies (Box 5)
- Flavor, E.S. Guthrie (Box 5)
- E.S. Guthrie, Cultured Cream (Box 5)
- E.S. Guthrie (Box 5)
- E.S. Guthrie, July 5, 1929, and Stark (Box 5)
- Theory of Churning (Box 5)
- III (Box 5)
- I - Starter (Box 5)
- Book II, Starter (Box 5)
- Deaeration vs. no deaeration, E.S. Guthrie, Daylight Studies, Cultured Cream, Sour Cream, last part of book (Box 5)
- Reports of scans of products received for any criticism, E.S. Guthrie (Box 5)
- Tied bundle of notes, no title (Box 5)
- IX, E.S. Guthrie, Dairy Bldg. (Box 5)
- Butter Experiments, McIneernery-Guthrie, Tucker (Box 5)
- E.S. Guthrie, III, Sour Cream (Box 5)
- Sour Cream IIIV, Sour Cream, Aug. 28, 1933, Dr. E.S. Guthrie, H. Vorperian (?) (Box 5)
- I, Sour Cream Theory of Churning II (Box 5)
- Primary Flavors of Milk, E.S. Guthrie (Box 5)
- Bankhead Jones Project - Scores of Butter Samples by E.S. Guthrie (Box 5)
- Ox. fl. 1950 (Box 5)
- Corrosin - Taylor Instrument Co., Ames St. Cor. Albert Ave., Rochester, E.S. Guthrie (Box 5)
- Letters recommending the Dairy Building be named Stocking Hall, 1945-1946 (Box 5)
- Three large felt banners, two 1923, one 1922, for judging at exposition of dairy products (Box 6)
- One large map of Hamptonburg (Box 6)
- Large drawing of residence of Geo. Gouge Campbell Hall, Hamptonburg Town, Organe Co., N.Y. (Box 6)
- Photograph approx 18" by 8" of creamery at Newfield (Box 6)
- Evelope containing: positive and negative photograph of heard of cows; photos of classes; pos. and neg. photograph of cow and calf; pos. and neg. photograph - milking scene, Argentina (Box 6)
- Envelope containing mounted photograph of Cornell Conference, Delhi Tech. Dairy Industry Seniors (Box 6)
- Envelope (small) of various slides, and pos. and neg. photographs, such as first butter factory, Campbell Hall, P.O., etc. (Box 6)
- Two photographs of wooden butter tubs (Box 6)
- Framed lithograph (?) of J.K. Brown (Box 6)
- Mounted photo.of various professors (?) taken in Robert's Hall around 1906-1907 (Box 6)
- Letter to Guthrie from Mrs. William A. Stocking, Aug. 13, 1948 (Box 6)
- Electrotype (?) (Box 6)
- Drawing (printed) of a milk process (?) (Box 6)
- Drawings on a sort of cloth-paper of milk equipment (?) (Box 6)
- More misc. photos and drawings (Box 6)
- "The Cornell Countryman," Vol. XLV, Mar. 1948, No. 6 (Box 6)
- Smaller box of glass plates (photographic) (Box 6)
- Other photographs of creameries (loose) (Box 6)
- Printing block (Box 6)
- Newspaper: The Newburgh News, Oct. 27, 1956 (Box 6)
- Notebook: E.S. Guthrie, 1958, Rancidity (Box 6)
- Photogrpahs (glossy prints) of Pine Grove Farm (Box 6)
- Four brochures of first butter factory (Box 6)
- Commencement Program for Ohio State University, Class of 1907 (Box 6)
- Magazine, "Cherry Burrell Circle," May 1949-June 1949 (Box 6)
- Magazine, "The Milk Products Journal," Aug. 1956 (Box 6)
- Butter score cards (Box 6)
- Misc. accounts? (Box 6)
- Excerpts from New York Produce Review and American Creamery (Box 6)
- Misc. papers, correp., clippings, drawings (Box 6)
- Storage Milk, Cream and whole milk powder (small notebook) (Box 6)
- Standardization of Sodium 2, 6 - Dichlorobenzenone-indophenol (small notebook) (Box 6)
- Book III, Sour Cream (small notebook) (Box 6)
- Accuracy of the Vapor-Odor Method of Grading Milk (small notebook) (Box 6)
- Book II, E.S. Guthrie (small notebook) (Box 6)
- Book I, 1961, Purchased Cultured Cream, E.S. Guthrie, Stocking Hall (small notebook) (Box 6)